## SHANGLIN GUO

linkedin.com/in/shanglin-guo | github.com/guoshanglin | guosl.com

#### **PROFILE**

MS Electrical Engineering student at Columbia University with extensive experience in IoT and embedded systems, laboratory experience in FPGA, Linux and computer network configurations. Familiar with networking standards (REST, CoAP) for IoT devices, and TCP/IP protocol stack (IP, TCP/UDP).

#### **EDUCATION**

Columbia University
M.S. in Electrical Engineering

New York, NY

Sep 2018 – Dec 2019 (Expected)

GPA 3.88/4.00

- Courses: Internet of Things, Computer Networking Laboratory, Embedded Systems
- Research: Wireless & Mobile Networking (WiMNet) Research Lab

# The Hong Kong Polytechnic University B.Eng (Hons) in Electronic & Information Engineering GPA 3.76/4.00

Kowloon, HK

June 2018

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Wireless & Mobile Networking (WiMNet) Research Lab, Columbia University Research Assistant

New York, NY

Feb 2019 – Present

- Participating in the Columbia FlexICoN (Full-duplex Wireless: From Integrated Circuits to Networks) project which focuses on the design and implementation of full-duplex wireless communication testbed
- Currently working on upgrading the custom-designed full-duplex radios, that consists of a full-duplex (FD) transceiver using the USRP N210 SDR and a customized RF canceller
- Focusing on embedded programming on the Arduino Due to interface with the RF canceller via SPI protocol, and optimizing the SPI performance on the Arduino Due

#### **Brno University of Technology**

Brno, CZ

Research Assistant

Jul 2017 - Aug 2017

- Developed and investigated node localization methods (RSSI, ToA) for Bluetooth wireless networks in C
- Implemented the localization methods on AVR microcontrollers as nodes, analyzed the result and optimized the localization methods based on the location error observed in lab experiments

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Musical Stimulus Visualization**

Feb 2019 – May 2019

- Implemented on the FPGA a memory-mapped peripheral, and communicated with the peripheral through C program running on the Linux kernel that can access a device driver
- Developed a C program that runs on an ARM-based hard processor system (HPS), performing a Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) and noise suppression on audio input received from a USB microphone
- Modified the device driver that implements an ioctl to mediate between the C program and the FPGA peripheral
- Designed a Serial-in, Parallel-out (SIPO) shift register in hardware to buffer the data input from software and output the parallel data to a VGA monitor for musical stimulus visualization

#### Juniper Networks/Comcast SDN Throwdown Competition 2019

Feb 2019

- Developed a creative solution using the Juniper Networks NorthStar SDN Controller, with a combination of networking and programming to solve real-world issues such as random link failures and load balancing
- Optimized the given network infrastructure, which consists of 2 servers and 12 routers across the US, and through monitoring and planning, finally achieved the dynamical provision of explicit routing paths using segment routing

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Language:** Python, SystemVerilog, C/C++, Java, MATLAB, HTML

System and OS: Linux/Unix, Windows, Android Platform: AWS, Microsoft Azure, GitHub